Marvin Tryon

7131 Paladin Way, Rio Linda, CA, 95673 * (916) 335-0415 * marvinatryonjr@gmail.com

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Focused recent graduate from a Full Stack Coding Bootcamp in Web Development & Software Engineering (4.0 GPA) at UC Davis, with 9+ years of work experience. Aiming to leverage academic experience and a proven knowledge of database design, emerging technologies, and web design to successfully fill the Software Engineer role at your company. Frequently praised as adaptable by my peers, I can be relied upon to help your company achieve its goals.

EDUCATION

UC DAVIS

Sacramento, CA

Full Stack Coding Bootcamp Web Development & Software Engineering (Jun 2019)

- **GPA:** 4.0
- Relevant Course: Algorithms I, II, Big O Notation, React.js
- Extracurricular Activity: Sunday League Soccer

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

QUANSIS SYSTEMS, LLC, Sacramento, CA

Front-End Engineer, Jun 2019 - Present

- Design, build, or maintain web sites, using authoring or scripting languages, content creation tools, management tools, and digital media.
- Evaluate code to ensure that it is valid, is properly structured, meets industry standards and is compatible with browsers, devices, or operating systems.
- Worked independently as the recognized technical architect on the maintenance of the largest and most complex SAN systems and acts as a leader on projects related to enterprise storage configuration services and enterprise backup solutions.

UC DAVIS, Sacramento, CA

Student, Nov 2018 - Jun 2019

- Tutor and assist fellow students individually or in small groups to help one another to master assignments and to reinforce learning concepts presented by Instructors and TAs.
- Use computers, audio-visual aids, and other equipment and materials to supplement presentations.
- LEARN

FREELANCE, Rio Linda, CA

Construction Worker, Sep 2016 - Nov 2018

- Shape or cut materials to specified measurements, using hand tools, machines, or power saws.
- Measure and mark cutting lines on materials, using a ruler, pencil, chalk, and marking gauge.
- Install structures or fixtures, such as windows, frames, floorings, trim, or hardware, using carpenters' hand or power tools.

UNITED STATES NAVY, Norfolk, VA

Operations Specialist, Jun 2012 - Sep 2016

- I maintained a secret clearance in this capacity and had access to various secure spaces--to include: Combat Information Center and the Chart Room.
- I was responsible for monitoring and maintaining various radar consoles; and, locating and tracking Air, Surface, and SubSurface contacts. I was qualified Navigation and Maneuvering Board Plotter.
- Underway, I was qualified Helmsman, Aft Lookout, ASWE Console Operator, Combat Systems Operational Sequencing System Technician, Search & Rescue Execution, and Combat Information Center Watch Supervisor.

- In port, my watch-standing qualifications included: Petty Officer of the Watch, TopSide Rover, Entry Control Point Sentry, and Duty Corpsman. For collateral duties, I was a Medical Training Team Member in the capacity of Advanced Stretcher Bearer.
- I also was a member of the Basic ShipBoard Intelligence Collection Team--qualified as Lookout, Recorder, and Photographer. My Out-of-Job scope qualifications included; but not limited to: Basic and Advanced Damage Control, Maintenance Person, Craftsman, Division Quality Assurance Officer, and Basic/Advanced First-Aid.

ROSEANNA'S ITALIAN FOOD, Krebs, OK

Specialty Cook, Aug 2010 - Jun 2012

- Weigh, measure, and mix ingredients according to recipes or personal judgment, using various kitchen utensils and equipment.
- Wash, peel, cut, and seed fruits and vegetables to prepare them for consumption.
- Carve and trim meats such as beef, veal, ham, pork, and lamb for hot or cold service, or for sandwiches.
- Bake breads, rolls, cakes, and pastries.
- Ensure food is stored and cooked at correct temperature by regulating temperature of ovens, broilers, grills, and roasters.

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Javascript
- Database Engineering
- React
- Leadership
- Communication

CREDENTIALS AND LICENSES

• Certificate of Completion, Full Stack Coding Bootcamp